<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<process>
    <processId>027</processId>
    <processName>
        <text xml:lang="en">Query End of Usage Date</text>
        <text xml:lang="de">Nutzungsende-Datum abrufen</text>
    </processName>
    <description>
        <text xml:lang="en">Querying the end-of-usage date of the TSE device. This date indicates when the TSE must be replaced according to regulations. It is independent of temporary locks or decommissioning status.</text>
        <text xml:lang="de">Abfrage des Nutzungsenddatums des TSE-Geräts. Dieses Datum gibt an, wann die TSE gemäß den Vorschriften ersetzt werden muss. Sie ist unabhängig von temporären Sperren oder Decommissioning-Status.</text>
    </description>
    <actors>
        <actor>
            <text xml:lang="en">User (any role)</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">Nutzer (beliebige Rolle)</text>
        </actor>
        <actor>
            <text xml:lang="en">TSE</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">TSE</text>
        </actor>
        <actor>
            <text xml:lang="en">Storage Medium</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">Speichermedium</text>
        </actor>
    </actors>
    <usedObjects>
        <object>
            <text xml:lang="en">TSE</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">TSE</text>
        </object>
        <object>
            <text xml:lang="en">Storage Medium</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">Speichermedium</text>
        </object>
        <object>
            <text xml:lang="en">End of Usage Date</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">Nutzungsende-Datum</text>
        </object>
        <object>
            <text xml:lang="en">Certificate</text>
            <text xml:lang="de">Zertifikat</text>
        </object>
    </usedObjects>
    <interfaceFunctions>
        <function>getEndOfLifeDate</function>
    </interfaceFunctions>
    <inputParameters>
    </inputParameters>
    <outputParameters>
        <parameter>
            <name>endOfUsageDate</name>
            <type>DateTime</type>
            <description>
                <text xml:lang="en">Date and time when the TSE usage must end according to regulations</text>
                <text xml:lang="de">Datum und Uhrzeit, an dem die TSE-Nutzung gemäß den Vorschriften beendet sein muss</text>
            </description>
        </parameter>
    </outputParameters>
    <usedDataObjects>
        <dataObject>DateTime</dataObject>
    </usedDataObjects>
    <possibleExceptions>
        <exception>ErrorDeviceNotInitialized</exception>
        <exception>ErrorStorageMediumDisconnected</exception>
        <exception>ErrorRetrievingEndOfLifeDateFailed</exception>
    </possibleExceptions>
    <references>
        <reference>BSI TR-03151-1 Chapter 3.4.5</reference>
        <reference>BSI TR-03153-1 Chapter 5.5.3 (Validity Period)</reference>
    </references>
    <notes>
        <text xml:lang="en">This is an optional function accessible to all users. The end-of-usage date is independent of temporary locks or decommissioning state - it is always available for planning purposes. Users should plan TSE replacement well before this date to ensure continuity of operations. This date is typically based on the certificate validity period.</text>
        <text xml:lang="de">Dies ist eine optionale Funktion, die für alle Nutzer zugänglich ist. Das Nutzungsende-Datum ist unabhängig von temporären Sperren oder Decommissioning-Status - es ist immer für Planungszwecke verfügbar. Nutzer sollten die TSE-Ersetzung lange vor diesem Datum planen, um die Geschäftskontinuität zu gewährleisten. Dieses Datum basiert typischerweise auf der Zertifikatsgültigkeitsdauer.</text>
    </notes>
</process>
